

Andreas Klein

Agile Coaching & Development

COLOGNE, GERMANY / +49 173 8888 987 / ANDY@IXIS.IO / WWW.IXIS.IO

Figuring out how to get Things done in larger Teams as a <u>certified Scrum Master</u>, Mentor or <u>Frontend Developer</u>, not just in the software Industry. I help Agencies and Companies to realize accessible Products with Value and with a Focus on happy People. I also enable <u>Conferences</u> to share Experiences.

Outside of the web, I'm a proud father of two beautiful children, a passionate freestyle skateboarder/snowboarder and I like the taste of good espresso.

If there is still time, I'm pushing our nonprofit organization makuyuni.org forward, which builds schools in the outback of Tanzania where kids have no ability to go to school!

My other Profiles on the web:



twitter.com/ixisio



github.com/ixisio



xing.com/andreas klein156



https://makuyuni.org

Skills

- Agile thinking
- 10 Years of experience in Frontend Development and Agile Product

Development

- Accessibility Workshops and Trainings
- Professional Scrum Master® (PSM)
- Scrum Product Owner (PSPO)
- Moderation and Communication Trainings
- Agile Coach & Mentor
- Scaling Scrum with multiple Teams (Nexus, Scaled Scrum, LESS, SAFe)
- **Change** Management for Agile Product Development Teams
- Frontend Development and Consulting
- SPAs with Javascript (TypeScript, React.js)
- Static Sites or Serverside Rendering with Next.js, Gatsby
- Component based and Micro-Service oriented Development
- Content APIs with Strapi, Storyblok, Contentful (Headless CMS)
- Serverside Webapplication with Node.js
- Responsive Webdevelopment with semantic HTML5 and CSS3
- Design Thinking
- · Workshops, Trainings and Coaching
- Kanban
- · Continuous Improvement

Project Experience

med.stream // React Application

- · Customer: med.stream GmbH
- Role: Front-End Developer

• Date: 2022

Technologies: React.js

https://med.stream/

Vivamo // Static Site, React Application

Customer: brandneo GmbHRole: Front-End Developer

• Date: 2022

· Technologies: React.js, Next.js, Strapi

Vorwerk // Physical Product Development

Customer: Vorwerk Elektrowerke GmbH Co. KGRole: Agile Product Development, Scrum Master

• Date: 2020 - 2021

https://www.vorwerk.de/

HDI AG // Digital insurance products

Customer: Avenga Germany GmbHRole: Agile Coaching, Scrum Master

• Date: 2019 - 2020

https://www.hdi.de

AXA AG // Digital insurance products

Customer: AXA AG

· Role: Agile Coaching, Scrum Master

• Date: 2019

https://www.axa.de

Vaillant Group // Connected Devices - IoT, Websites

Customer: Vaillant Group Business Services GmbH

Role: Agile Coaching, Scrum Master

• Date: 2017 - 2018

https://www.vaillant-group.com

Toom Baumarkt // Websites & Shops

Customer: Rewe Group, Fork GmbH
 Rele: Agile Coaching, Front and Archite

• Role: Agile Coaching, Frontend Architect

• Date: 2016

• Technologies: Scrum, ES6, React.js

https://www.toom.de/

Aktion Mensch // Accessibility Workshop, Training

· Customer: Aktion Mensch e.V., Trusted Shops GmbH

• Role: Workshop Speaker

• Date: 2016

Topics: Accessibility

https://www.aktion-mensch.de/ http://www.trustedshops.de/

Billiger-Mietwagen.de // React Application

· Customer: Billiger-Mietwagen.de, SilverTours GmbH

Role: Front-End Architect

• Date: 2016

Technologies: React.js

https://www.billiger-mietwagen.de/

.. Ask me if you want to see the years 2009 to 2015.

Work Experience

2016 - present	Agile Coaching & Development (Freelance) www.ixis.io
2009 - 2016	Front-End Developer (Freelance) www.ixis.io
2011 - 2014	Frontend Developer (nexum AG) www.nexum.de
2009 - 2011	Application Developer eLearning (German Sport University Cologne) www.dshs-koeln.de

Education

2008 - 2011 Study of Physics - University of Cologne (until 2009)

Magisterium

Study of Sports and Performance - German Sport

University Cologne

Bachelor of Science

1998 - 2007

Comprehensive school, Willy-Brandt Cologne *Graduation from high school*



Cologne, last updated 30 March 2022, Andreas Klein